#Encodergasm Presents
～
（テディ･ボマー）フッ フフッ
（スパイク）忘れもんだぜ
You forgot something.
A-As you can see, I'm just some old man.
わ 私は見てのとおりの
いい年のおやじですよ
あいにく 子供もいませんし
Unfortunately, I don't have any children, either...
あんたのだなんて言ってないぜ
I never said it was yours.
ああ お客さんの
じゃあ 預かって…
Oh, was it a customer's?  I will hold it, then...
（スパイク）
どうだい？ 一軒 行かないか？
How about it?
Wanna go somewhere?
ベッドに入るには
まだ早いだろう？
It's a little to early to go to bed.
私は早寝早起きなんでね
I'm an early riser.  I sleep early.
規則正しい生活なら
うってつけの場所があるぜ
If you want a prim and proper life, I have just the place for you.
三食 ボディーガード付きで
ただっていうホテルだ
A hotel where you get three meals and a bodyguard, all for free.
I'm sure that's impossible without a reservation.
予約もなしじゃ無理でしょう？
ふん　ホテル刑務所だよ
テディ･ボマー
I'm talking about Hotel PRISON, Teddy Bomber.
I'd rather not, Spike Spiegel.
それは遠慮したいな
スパイク･スピーゲル
Oh, you know me?
おっ 知ってんのか？
It's a popular story among criminals...
（テディ･ボマー）
賞金首の間じゃ もっぱらの評判だ
君とアンディにだけは
捕まりたくないってね
...that we never want to be caught by you, or by Andy.
アンディ？
Andy?
私は目的は果たす！
I will fulfill my objective!
（スパイク）爆発は しないぜ
It won't blow up.
点火ピンは抜いといたからな
I took out the ignition pin.
うおっ うっ ぐはあ うあああ！
3 million woolongs, graciously accepted.
300万ウーロン いただき
クマは１匹じゃない
That's not the only bear.
お前も死ぬぞ
You'll die, too.
（テディ･ボマー）
死ぬほど好きなのさ
I love them to death.
なんで そんなに爆破したいかね
Why do you want to blow stuff up so much?
知りたいか？
私は警告しているのだ
You wanna know?  I am giving a warning.
知りたいか？
私は警告しているのだ
I am ringing a bell of warning!
警鐘を鳴らしているのだ
Alright, be mindful of what I say!
いいか？ 心して聞くがいい！
Andy!
アンディ
アンディ？
Andy?
（アンディ）
チッチッチッチッチッチッ
ワイアット･アープと呼んでくれ
Call me Wyatt Earp.
（アンディ）ユー 連続爆破魔
テディ･ボマー
YOU!  Teddy Bomber, serial bomber!
あ 俺が？
ME?!
今日 ここに
爆弾を仕掛けるということは―
The fact that you'd plant a bomb here today was easy...
ユーの犯罪周期を計算すれば
ミーには簡単に分かることだ
...for me to figure out after calculating your criminal cycles.
You don't think that's him?
（スパイク）
あいつだとは思わねえのか？
He's a security guard!
彼はガードマンじゃないか
顔をよく見ろ！
Just look at his face!
In this day and age, a face means nothing.
この時代
顔なんか当てにならないさ
（スパイク）それじゃ
何を根拠に言ってんだよ
Then what is the basis of your theory?!
That is...
それは あ… 私の勘
そう インスピレーション
...my gut instinct.  Yes, INSPIRATION!
おおい 待て！
Hey, wait!
WAIT!
ウェイト！
（スパイク）
うおっ ああああーっ！
アウチッ
OH SHIT!
That's why I said Teddy Bomber was THAT guy, you idiot!
（スパイク）
だから テディ･ボマーは―
あっちだって言ってんだろ
この野郎
DANGEROUS!
（アンディ）デンジャラス！
ふう！ 危ないところだった
That was a close one.
Giddyup!
ハイヨー！ フウー
A horse?
（ジェット）馬か
馬だよ
Yeah, a horse.
A horse, huh?
（フェイ）馬ねー
買い出しのついでに
捕まえてくるなんて言って―
I thought something was fishy when you said you...
...would nab that guy as part of your foraging trip.
怪しいと思ったのよ
What do you mean by that?
それ どういう意味だよ？
You used up the food money for all four of us, didn't you?
４人分の食費 使い込んだでしょ？
Oh, come on...
あのな
What did you use it on?
何に使ったのよ？
If you think I'm lying, explain THIS on my back!
（スパイク）
うそだって言うなら背中のこいつは
どうやって付いたんだよ？
All right, I hear ya.
分かった 分かった
The horse I can believe.
馬は まだ いいとして…
いいの？
You can?
カウボーイスタイルの
カウボーイってのは―
But, you have to be more creative than a cowboy in a cowboy outfit.
ひねりが なさすぎる
Is that the problem?
そういう問題かしら
Now if he was dressed like a samurai...
いっそ 侍姿だったとかな
フフ まだ信じられるか
...that would be more plausible.
Here he is... Little Andy!
（エド）いたよー アンディちゃん
（スパイク）おっ
ＹＭＣＡに入ってる人なのな
アンディちゃんは
Little Andy is a guy in the YMCA...
A Christian?
（スパイク）クリスチャンか？
Nope.  Young Men's Cowboy Association!
（エド）違うよ　ヤングマンズ･
カウボーイ･アソシエーションだよ
Oh?  Such a thing exists?
へえー そんなのあるんだ
But, he got kicked out soon after joining.
（エド）
でも すぐ除名されてるのなー
The reason?
理由は？
Because he caused others trouble!
他の人の迷惑だから
Of course!
当然だ
Andy von de Oniyate... the noble son of Oniyate Ranch.
アンディ･フォン･デ･オニヤテ
オニヤテ牧場の御曹司か！
結構 いい男じゃない
Hey, he's pretty cute.
123 cases of property damage.  89 cases of destruction of public property.
（エド）器物損壊 123件
公共物破壊 89件
Many, many people injured.
ケガ人 たくさん！
A good match for SOMEONE we know.
誰かと いい勝負だわ
I told you he existed!
いただろうが
分かった 分かった
All right, I hear ya.
（スパイク）反応は？
Any reactions?
（ジェット）まだ出ない
None yet.
However...
しかし この大人数の中で
爆破されちゃ たまらねえな
We can't let it explode with all these people around.
（スパイク）
やつの目的はビルだけだ
殺人は お好みじゃない
His only target is the building.
He's not one for murder.
（ジェット）信用できるかね
You think we can trust him?
Guys like him are often concerned with their sense of style.
（スパイク）
自分の美学に こだわるんだよ
ああいうやつは
（ジェット）ま 身を隠すには
絶好のパーティーだがな
Well, this is the perfect party to hide yourself.
ここに爆弾魔が来るって知ってる？
Did you know that a serial bomber is gonna come here?
To tell the truth, I didn't know.
本当 言うと 初耳です
Well, he's coming.
来るのよ
（ジェット）ヘイ
Hey!
ラブアンドピースだぜ 世の中は
The world is about LOVE AND PEACE!
よう
Yo.
な なぜ私が分かった？
H-How did you know it was me?
こいつがパパを見つけてくれたのさ
This led the way to its papa.
どっちにしろ
分かったと思うけどな
I think I woulda known in either case.
諦めが悪いな 君たちも
You guys just don't quit, do you?
Speak for yourself.
（スパイク）それは お前だろう
（ジェット）
なんで そんなに爆破したい？
Why do you want to blow things up so much?
ふん 知りたいか？
私は警告しているのだ
Ya wanna know?
I am giving out a warning.
ふん 知りたいか？
私は警告しているのだ
Listen, in this world, the root of all evil...
いいか？ この世の諸悪の
根源である… うっ
（人々のざわめき）
A horse...
馬？
A cowboy...
カウボーイ
（アンディ）
ヘイ！ ユー テディ･ボマー
HEY, YOU!  Teddy Bomber!
うっ 俺が？
M-Me?!
だから言ったろ
See, I told you.
Or is it you over there?
それとも そっちか？
Do you have NO memory?
（スパイク）
お前 記憶力ないのか？
昨日 会ったばっかりだろ
We met just yesterday!
ん？ 覚えがないな
I have no recollection.
（スパイク）てんめぇ！
YOU!
あのー お客さま
馬は困るんですが…
Um, sir, your horse is an inconvenience.
It does prove rather troublesome for our other customers.
他のお客さまのご迷惑に
オー マイ 愛馬オニキスは
ただの馬ではない
OH!  My beloved steed Onyx is no ordinary horse!
At times, she sets my troubled mind at ease; at others she is my chess partner.
時には心のよりどころとなり
時にはチェスの相手として…
（スパイク）
馬がチェスをするかよ！
Like horses play chess!
It doesn't matter either way.
（ジェット）
どっちでも いいだろが
私は無視されるのが―
I detest being IGNORED!!
嫌いだー！
（人々の悲鳴）
What happened to his sense of style?!
美学は どうなったんだよ
（ジェット）落ち着け！
落ち着けって うええ ええ
Calm down!  I'm telling you to calm down!
ラブアンドピースだ
Love and peace, man!
Such a lovely horse.
（フェイ）すてきな馬だこと
お気に召しましたか？
Do you like her?
Would you like to be my escort?
送ってくださる？
Now, get behind me.
さあ 後ろへ
野郎！
You little!
（馬のいななき）
どわぁー
In my life, I've never seen such a...
生まれて初めて見たわ
こんな悪趣味な部屋
...tasteless room.
Now, I present you with my special Son of a Gun Stew.
さあ
私の特製サノバガンシチューを
ごちそうしよう
I'm sure you'll find it extremely delicious.
ほっぺた 落ちちまうぜ
Um...  So, why are you a bounty hunter?
あの どうして
賞金稼ぎなんか？
If you're so rich, uh, I mean if you have so much comfort in your life...
こんなに金持ち…
あ いや あ
生活にゆとりが おありなのに
なぜ？ そうだな
Why...  Let's see...
ビコーズ それは私に似合うから
Because... it suits me.
牛を追い込むカウボーイの
心意気がね
That feeling a cowboy gets when he corners a bull.
Oh... but you don't have to go after such a dangerous bounty, do you?
ああー でも あんな危険な
賞金首じゃなくっても―
いいんじゃありません？
（ジェット）
なんでテディ･ボマーに
手を出すやつがいないのか―
I know why nobody wants to go after Teddy Bomber.
分かったよ
（スパイク）ああ？
爆発の巻き添え
食らいたくないんだよ みんな
Nobody wants to get a piece of the explosion!
You think we can worry about that?
そんなもん 気にしてられるか
Yes!  I don't worry about things like that!
そう 私はそんなこと気にしない
Once I set my mind on something, I can see NOTHING else!
これと決めたら
他はナッシング！ 見えないのさ
I think I've seen this personality somewhere before...
なーんか
どっかで聞いたような性格
（アンディ）えっ？
（フェイ）ああ
いえ オホ オホホホホ
Oh, nothing...
Now!
（アンディ）さあ
（フェイ）は？
君の瞳に―
Here's lookin' at...
映った僕に乾杯
...my reflection, kid.
か 乾杯…
Cheers...
（ジェット）んー？
あい お土産
Hi, I got a souvenir.
Yippie!  A souvenir!  A souvenir!
（エド）わーい お土産 お土産ー
俺は食わねえぞ こんなもん
I ain't gonna eat THAT!
晩飯にするか
Guess this is for dinner...
I will NOT eat that!
腹 壊すぞ
Your stomach will suffer.
（ジェット）しかし やつの何が
お前をそこまで熱くさせるかね
But, what about him makes you so hotheaded?
They're too similar.
似たもの同士なのよ
同族嫌悪ってやつ
You know how similar people hate each other.
俺のどこが あの
くそばか野郎に似てるってんだよ？
What part of me is similar to that shit-headed idiot?!
The part that makes you damn troublesome.
はた迷惑なところだな
（フェイ）あ ビッグショット
もう始まってるわ
Oh, Big Shot has already started.
Well, the last thing we have to tell you is info about TB, Teddy Bomber.
（パンチ）
さーて 最後にお伝えするのは
テディ･ボマー 通称ＴＢの情報だ
Can you believe it?  We got a message from him, just for this show!
（ジュディ）
なんと 彼から番組宛てに
メッセージをいただいたのよ
What?  Is that for real?
ひい そりゃ本物かい？
Um, let's see...
えっとー 何々？
“予告状”
WARNING.  "This is for those that have made fun of me."
“私をばかにしてくれた連中に
告げる”
"My next job is your last chance."
“次の仕事が最後のチャンスだ”
“今度は お前らも
花火のように爆破してやる”
"This time, I'll blow YOU up as well, like fireworks."
おやおや 穏やかじゃないね
My, my, he doesn't sound calm.
"That is, if you know where I will set up next."
“次に仕掛ける場所が
分かればの話だが フフフ”
"Heh, heh, heh."
“最後に私の
本当の目的を教えてやろう”
"And lastly, I will tell you my true intent..."
（パンチ）おおっとー
残念ながら時間が来ちまった
Whoops!  Looks like time is up for us.  That's all for today.
今日は ここまでだ
あーん 全部 読めなくて
ごめんなさい ＴＢ
I'm sorry I couldn't read all of it, TB.
Well, until next time...
じゃあ また この時間に！
Good luck!
グッドラック
The next one's in City Hall...
（エド）次は市役所だよー
You figured it out already?
もう分かったのか？
ＴＢはね
高いビルの順番に壊してんの
TB is blowing up tall buildings starting with the tallest one...
The reason was THAT simple?
（フェイ）
そんな単純な理由だったの？
どうする？ 俺は降りるぞ
What are you gonna do?  I'm getting outta this one!
（フェイ）私も　パス
I'm gonna pass, too.
Spike, what are you going to do?
（ジェット）
スパイク お前 どうすんだ？
Like you have to ask?
（スパイク）決まってんだろ！
遅い！
LATE!
おのれ
Dammit!  If they think they can get away with this, they are sorely mistaken.
やつら このままで済むと思ったら
大間違い…
１人か？
You alone?
よくも のこのこと現れてくれたな
How dare you take so much time to get here!
待て
Wait!
Wrong guy...
人違いか
I have never intended humans as targets!
私は あえて人間を
標的にしたことはない
But, you guys are different!
だが お前たちは別だ！
お前たちのようなやつらは…
Guys like you deserve...
しっ！
He's here...
来たな
ユー 貴様か
YOU!  It was you!
（スパイク）やっと覚えてくれたか
いつも いつも…
So you finally remember me.
You always-
（アンディ）いつも いつも
人の前に割り込んで―
You ALWAYS butt in and get in my way!
邪魔ばかりしおって
ぬっ 邪魔は お前だろうが！
YOU'RE the one that's in the way!
２人そろったところで
聞かせてやろう
Now that I have both of you here, I will tell you.
The reason why I continue to blow buildings up.  That is because...
私が なぜ爆破を繰り返すのか？
それは…
今日こそは
はっきりと決着を着けてやる
Today, we are going to settle the score once and for all.
WHAT?!  That's MY line!
なにい こっちのせりふだ！
Listen to what I have to say!!
聞けい！ 人の話を！
Shut up!
（２人）うるさい！
And you are?  WHO ARE YOU?!
お前は誰だ？ フーアーユー？
C-Can't you guys put some effort into your work?!
お前ら真面目に仕事しろ！
（馬のいななき）
あいつを捕まえるのが先だ！
We have to catch HIM first!
Wait!
待て おい
（スパイク）だあっ くそっ
（アンディ）ふあっ！
（テディ･ボマー）
君たちは私を甘く見すぎている
You guys take me too lightly.
そのエレベーターの扉が開くことは
もうない
That elevator's doors will never open again.
And once it starts moving, that's the end.  It will never stop.
そして動き出したが最後
二度と止まらない
At the top floor, my cute little bears will greet you.
最上階では
私のかわいいクマちゃんたちが―
君たちを出迎えてくれる
そして―
So, the moment that the elevator reaches the top floor...
エレベーターが
最上階に着いた そのとき！
ドカーン！
BOOM!
ヒャーッハッハッハッハッハッハ
Well, live what little you have of your life left without regret!
まあ 残り少ない人生―
悔いの残らぬよう
過ごしてくれたまえ
では グッドラック
Farewell, and good luck.
安心しろ
Rest assured.
I understand.  I KNOW how he does things.
やつの手はずはアイノウ！
分かってる
（スパイク）慌てるな
やつの手はずは分かって… ん？
Don't worry.  I know how he does...
変更されていた非常用の暗証番号は
昼間のうちに私が戻しておいた
This afternoon, I reverted the secret emergency...
...code that had been changed.  YEAH!
イエイッ
I reverted it this afternoon!
俺が昼間に戻しておいたんだよ
（アンディ）うん？
変えて 変えて―
Change after change...
...means it's back to where it started!!
結局 元に
戻ってるんじゃねえかよ！
ああ！ よせ ばか野郎！
Stop, you idiot!
どうする？ どうするんだ？
オー ノォー！
What do we do, what do we do?!  OH, NO!!
ぐは　よせ このくそが！
きついだろうが
Wah, stop, shit, it's too tight!
（アンディ）ユーこそ 邪魔だよ
YOU are in the way!
（スパイク）何？ どけよ！ こら
What?!  Get outta the way, dammit!!
Farewell...
さらばだ
Come to think of it, they were brave young men.
思えば勇敢な若者たちだった
（アンディ）おいっ イテッ！
くそっ！ ふっ うっ
They're climbing... those two monkeys...
（フェイ）登ってるわ　猿が２匹
They like high places.
高いとこが好きなんだな
So they ARE similar.
やっぱ似てるわけよ
Let's just go back.
とっとと帰るか
んじゃ 私 こいつ引き渡してくわ
Then I'll go turn him in.
YOU don't even deserve to be called a cowboy.
ユーはカウボーイの
風上にも置けないやつだ
お前だけは絶対に許せねえ
I will never forgive you.
（スパイク）うわああっ
WOW!
ワーオ！
I lose...
負けたよ
すごいパンチだった
That was some punch!
You are a true cowboy.
お前こそ 本物のカウボーイだ
今日限りでカウボーイを引退する
As of today, I will no longer be a cowboy.
これが本当の脱帽だ
This really is a hats-off!
So... what are ya gonna do now?
で どうすんだよ？ お前
新しい生き方を見つけるだろう
I will no doubt find a new way of life.
See you, Space Cowboy!
シーユー スペースカウボーイ
（馬のいななき）
（スパイク）まあ しょせん
ぼんぼんの道楽よ
Well, it was only a rich boy's hobby.
His level... no... rank... was really no match for me.
俺とはレベルっちゅうか
ランクっちゅうの？ 違うからよ
Hey, are ya listening?
おい 聞いてんのかよ？
Yeah, yeah.
はいはい
（スパイク）結局は
俺の敵じゃなかったってことよ
So, he just wasn't any enemy of mine.
Of course, I never had him in my line of sight.
もっとも
最初から眼中にはなかったけどな
ひひーん！
ぱかっ ぱかっ ぱかっ
Hey, are you listening?
聞いてんのかよ？
Yeah, yeah.
（ジェット）はいはい
（警官）はあー しかし―
But anyway...
お前も なんでそんなに
爆破したかったんだ？
Why did you want to blow stuff up so much?
私は警告したかったのだ
I wanted to give a warning...
哲学なき資本主義が生み出した
全ての無駄に対して…
...against all the unnecessary waste created by capitalism lacking philosophy.
Planets that needlessly get colonized.
無駄に開拓される惑星
無駄に流れ続けるメディア
Media that needlessly get circulated.
そして その象徴である
無駄に高いビル
And buildings that are needlessly tall to symbolize all of this!
それを破壊することによって―
And by destroying them, I wanted to raise...
本来の開拓者の在り方を
問いただしたかったのだ
...the question of how a true pioneer should be.
（アンディ）
待て 待て 待てーい！
Wait, wait, WAIT!
アンディ！
Andy!
ムサシと呼んでくれい
Call me...  MUSASHI!
ゴー！ ジロウマルー！
Go, JIROUMARU!
（馬のいななき）
でも―
But...
It was all a waste, wasn't it?
そんなこと無駄だったんだな
フフッ
（馬のいななき）
Too much time has passed by...
Aishiteta to nageku niwa
...to lament that we were deeply in love.
Amarinimo toki wa sugite shimatta
The wind keeps blowing, while my heart...
Mada kokoro no hokorobi wo
...cannot heal all the tears in it.
lyasenu mama kaze ga fuiteru
Someone, cry for me with parched eyes.
Kawaita hitomi de dareka naite kure
The real folk blues.
The real folk blues
I only want to know what true sadness is.
Honto no kanashimi ga shiritai dake
Sitting in muddy water...
Doro no kawa ni tsukatta
...isn't such a bad life...
Jinsei mo waruku wa nai
...if it ends after the first time...
Ichido kiri de owaru nara
～
（アンディ）今回のミーの活躍
しっかり見てくれたかな？
So, did you pay close attention to me and my wonderful role?
Hey, wait a minute...
（スパイク）おい ちょっと待てよ
Now, the next episode, the next story...
（アンディ）さあて 次回の
ネクストストーリーだが…
Why are YOU doing the preview?
（スパイク）なんで お前が
予告やってんだよ
（アンディ）またしてもミー
つまりアンディが大活躍
Once again, it's time for me, Andy, to have an active role in the story!
（スパイク）お前の出番は
終わったんだって
Your turn on the stage is already over!
Now that I'm a space samurai, watch me completely crush cowboys left and right!
（アンディ）
スペース侍となったミーが―
カウボーイたちを
ばったばったとなぎ倒す
You're not appearing in the show anymore!
（スパイク）もう出ないんだよ！
（アンディ）
次回 カウボーイビバップ
「アンディの逆襲」
Next episode of Cowboy Bebop: Andy Strikes Back!
（スパイク）
そんなタイトルじゃねえだろう！
The title is nothing like that!
Please look forward to it!
（アンディ）お楽しみに